<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<page title="News">
  <section title="2011">
    <news>
      <item date="01. Sep 2011">
        Stuck in Pingus? Full <a href="http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL85CB546B69E1E313">walkthrough videos for the Tutorial Island and the Halloween 2007 levelset</a> are available on Youtube.        
      </item>

      <item date="31. Aug 2011">
        The Pingus source code repository has been moved to Git and is now located at 
        <a href="http://code.google.com/p/pingus/source/checkout">code.google.com</a>.
      </item>
    </news>
  </section>
  
  <section title="2010">
    <news>
      <item date="12. Apr 2010">
        The webpage got a little relayout.
      </item>

      <item date="18. Mar 2010">
        Pingus 0.7.3 is released, nothing new in terms of gameplay, just
        some fixes to make it work with newer incarnations of GCC.
      </item>
    </news>
  </section>

  <section title="2007">
    <news>
      <item date="31. Oct 2007">
        Pingus 0.7.2 is released, this release features 8 brand new
        Halloween levels along with numerous smaller bug fixes.

        <ul>
          <li>added support for levelsets</li>
          <li>added 8 new levels in the form of a halloween levelset</li>
          <li>added window resize support to the editor (use --allow-resize)</li>
          <li>added minimap to the editor</li>
          <li>scroll wheel support to change the actions</li>
          <li>right and middle button now both scroll</li>
          <li>'jumper dying on landing' bug fixed</li>
          <li>numerous other small bug fixes</li>
        </ul>
      </item>

      <item date="23. Sep 2007">
        Pingus 0.7.1 is released, this is the second release based on
        SDL and among some small bug fixes, it also contains a brand new
        level editor rewritten from scratch. Other new things in this
        release:

        <ul>
          <li>faster sprite drawing, so more overall fps</li>
          <li>level editor rewritten from scratch</li>
          <li>level loading from command line fixed</li>
          <li>numerous other command line parsing bugs fixed</li>
          <li>separate images for gfx and colmap are used again</li>
          <li>input subsystem rewritten from scratch, supports now gamepads,
            usbmice, wiimote (some of those might unfinished and not enabled by
            default)</li>
        </ul>
      </item>

      <item date="25. Aug 2007">
        Pingus 0.7.0 is released, this is the first working version of
        Pingus that is based on SDL. New things in this release:
        
        <ul>
          <li>switch from ClanLib to SDL</li>
          <li>new anti-aliased fonts</li>
          <li>better support for resolutions larger then 800x600 (see --geometry WxH option)</li>
          <li>s-expression based file format (converter scripts are available)</li>
          <li>PPC and 64bit support</li>
          <li>language support for Czech, German, Finish, Italian, Norwegian,
            Serbian, Turkish, Danish, Dutch, Spanish, Fench and Polish</li>
          <li>level editor temporarly removed</li>
          <li>a little less fps then the ClanLib version</li>
          <li>no new levels or other main features</li>
        </ul>
      </item>

      <item date="25. Jun 2007">
        Pingus goes multi-touch, some people at the RWTH Aachen used
        Pingus gfx in the creation of their Table Lemmings game, you can find screenshots 
        at <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/davidh/567995242/">Flickr</a> and at their page at the 
        <a href="http://media.informatik.rwth-aachen.de/tiki-index.php?page=table-lemmings">RWTH
          Aachen</a>.
      </item>
    </news>
  </section>
  <p style="text-align: right"><a href="news_old.html">Older News...</a></p>
</page>
