<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="default.xsl"?>
<page title="News">
  <news>
    <item date="18. Mar 2010">
      Pingus 0.7.3 is released, nothing new in terms of gameplay, just
      some fixes to make it work with newer incarnations of GCC.
    </item>

    <item date="31. Oct 2007">
      Pingus 0.7.2 is released, this release features 8 brand new
      Halloween levels along with numerous smaller bug fixes.

      <ul>
        <li>added support for levelsets</li>
        <li>added 8 new levels in the form of a halloween levelset</li>
        <li>added window resize support to the editor (use --allow-resize)</li>
        <li>added minimap to the editor</li>
        <li>scroll wheel support to change the actions</li>
        <li>right and middle button now both scroll</li>
        <li>'jumper dying on landing' bug fixed</li>
        <li>numerous other small bug fixes</li>
      </ul>
    </item>

    <item date="23. Sep 2007">
      Pingus 0.7.1 is released, this is the second release based on
      SDL and among some small bug fixes, it also contains a brand new
      level editor rewritten from scratch. Other new things in this
      release:

      <ul>
        <li>faster sprite drawing, so more overall fps</li>
        <li>level editor rewritten from scratch</li>
        <li>level loading from command line fixed</li>
        <li>numerous other command line parsing bugs fixed</li>
        <li>separate images for gfx and colmap are used again</li>
        <li>input subsystem rewritten from scratch, supports now gamepads,
          usbmice, wiimote (some of those might unfinished and not enabled by
          default)</li>
      </ul>
    </item>

    <item date="25. Aug 2007">
      Pingus 0.7.0 is released, this is the first working version of
      Pingus that is based on SDL. New things in this release:
      
      <ul>
        <li>switch from ClanLib to SDL</li>
        <li>new anti-aliased fonts</li>
        <li>better support for resolutions larger then 800x600 (see --geometry WxH option)</li>
        <li>s-expression based file format (converter scripts are available)</li>
        <li>PPC and 64bit support</li>
        <li>language support for Czech, German, Finish, Italian, Norwegian,
          Serbian, Turkish, Danish, Dutch, Spanish, Fench and Polish</li>
        <li>level editor temporarly removed</li>
        <li>a little less fps then the ClanLib version</li>
        <li>no new levels or other main features</li>
      </ul>
    </item>

    <item date="25. Jun 2007">
      Pingus goes multi-touch, some people at the RWTH Aachen used
      Pingus gfx in the creation of their Table Lemmings game, you can find screenshots 
      at <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/davidh/567995242/">Flickr</a> and at their page at the 
      <a href="http://media.informatik.rwth-aachen.de/tiki-index.php?page=table-lemmings">RWTH
        Aachen</a>.
    </item>

    <item date="15. Jan 2007">
      Porting Pingus to SDL is in progress, some spelling fixes for the FAQ
    </item>
    
    <item date="11. Feb 2006">
      Time for some news, current plans for Pingus look like this:

      <ul>
        <li>Jave27 is currently trying to get the latest version in a release ready state</li>

        <li>Grumbel opened a new branch in SVN called pingus-sdl, this
          is supposed to port Pingus to SDL, level file format will
          switch to S-Expr instead of XML
        </li>
      </ul>
    </item>

    <item date="09. Apr 2004">
      It's been a long time without any updates, so there's a couple of news to note here.
      <ul>
        <li>Pingus got elected GotM for April at <a href="http://www.happypenguin.org">The Linux Game Tome</a> and a 0.7 release with many new features may be expected soon.</li>
	<li>Pingus CVS was replaced by <a href="http://subversion.tigris.org">Subversion</a></li>
        <li>There will be a new release on the stable branch (0.6.1) very soon now, planned date is 15.04.2004 - cross your fingers and hope. :-)</li>
        <li>We've got now a <a href="http://pingus.seul.org/level_comment_tool/index.php">Level Comment Tool</a> where you can rate all levels which are delivered with Pingus.</li>
      </ul>
    </item>

    <item date="14. Sep 2003">
      A added little button in the bottom left corner of the webpage
      that allows you to <a
                            href="https://www.paypal.com/xclick/business=grumbel%40gmx.de&amp;item_name=Pingus+donation&amp;no_note=1&amp;tax=0&amp;currency_code=EUR">donate
        via Paypal</a>.
    </item>

    <item date="16. Apr 2003">
      Pingus 0.6.0 is finally out, has taken longer as expected, but
      here it is. It contains one island with 22 playable tutorial
      levels. This is the first playable release ever of Pingus.
    </item>

    <item date="12. Apr 2003">
      A second prerelease of Pingus 0.6.0 is out, named 0.6.0rc2,
      final 0.6.0 release is expected to be finished this weekend.
    </item>

    <item date="7. Apr 2003">
      A first prerelease of Pingus 0.6.0 is out, named 0.6.0rc1
    </item>

    <item date="21. Mar 2003">
      After some downtime the Pingus CVS repository is up and running
      again. But since its now in another CVSROOT people with a
      checkout need either to re checkout it or editor they
      <tt>CVS/Root</tt> files a bit, more info is available <a href="http://mail.gnu.org/archive/html/pingus-devel/2003-03/msg00063.html">here</a>.
    </item>

    <item date="5. Mar 2003">
      Another IRC Meeting is scheduled for the end of this week (07.
      Mar 2003) on Friday, 18:00 GMT. Server and channel stay the as
      with the last one, see below. same. Everybody is welcome.
    </item>

    <item date="26. Feb 2003">
      IRC Meeting planed for the next Saturday. For details see below and the <a href="contact.html">Contact Section</a> of this site.<br/><br/>
      <table>
        <tr><td>Server:</td><td><a href="http://freenode.net">irc.freenode.net</a> 6667</td></tr>
        <tr><td>Channel:</td><td>#pingus</td></tr>
        <tr><td>Date:</td><td>Saturday, 1. March 2003</td></tr>
        <tr><td>Time:</td><td>21:00 <a href="http://greenwichmeantime.com/">GMT</a></td></tr>
      </table>
    </item>

    <item date="22. Dec 2002">
      Rumour is that a new, finally playable, release will come out in
      the next days... even so this isn't officially confirmed you
      might cross your fingers and it will probably happen.
    </item>

    <item date="21. Dec 2002">
      The Webpage got finally a complete redesign, this took, as
      always, longer than expected, but anyway here it is. If you want
      to know how this page is generated you can look at the xml
      source and the Makefiles in the <a
                                         href="http://savannah.nongnu.org/cvs/?group=pingus">Savanna Web
        CVS tree</a>.
    </item>
  </news>

  <p style="text-align: right"><a href="news_old.html">Older News...</a></p>
</page>
