<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="default.xsl"?>
<page title="Welcome">
  <section title="What is Pingus?">
    <p>
      Pingus is a free Lemmings-like game covered under
      the <a href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html">GNU
      GPL</a>. It features currently 22 playable levels and runs under
      a wide variety of operating systems (Linux, Windows, etc.)
    </p>
  </section>

  <section title="The Game">
    <p>
      Pingus has started at the end of 1998 with the simple goal to
      create a Free (as in freedom, not as in free beer)
      Lemmings<sup>tm</sup> clone. The <em>Free</em> means you get the
      sources and are allowed and encouraged to change and distribute
      them. You basically get everything that I used to create this
      game. In the years it has grown than quite a bit over the
      original goal and become something more than just a clone, we
      have original artwork, a built-in level editor, new actions,
      multiplayer and a few other features.
    </p>

    <p>
      If you don't know Lemmings<sup>tm</sup>, here comes a short
      introduction. Its a puzzle game developed in 1991 by <a
	href="http://www.mobygames.com/company/sheet/companyId,146/">DMA
	Design</a>. The player takes command in the game of a bunch of
      small animals and has to guide them around in levels. Since the
      animals walk on their own, the player can only influence them by
      giving them commands, like <em>build a bridge</em>,
      <em>dig a hole</em> or <em>redirect all animals in the
	other direction</em>. The goal of each level is to reach the
      exit, for fix multiple combination of commands are necessary.
      The game is presented in a 2D site view. For more information
      you might want to visit <a
	href="http://www.kallex.de/lemmings/">Lemmings<sup>tm</sup>
	fanpage</a>
    </p>

    <p>
      While Pingus is based on the idea of Lemmings<sup>tm</sup>, it
      has included some other ideas, which weren't presented in the
      original Lemmings<sup>tm</sup>, like the worldmap or secret
      levels, which might be familiar from games the Super Mario World
      and other Nintendo games. We have also a few new actions, like
      the jumper which weren't presented in the original game. To get
      an impression of the look of the Pingus game you might want to
      have a look at some <a href="screenshots.html">screenshots</a>.
    </p>

<!--    <A HREF="http://de.nedstat.net/viewstat.asp?name=pingus"><IMG
	SRC="http://de.nedstat.net/scripts/nedstat.dll?name=pingus"
	WIDTH="22" HEIGHT="22" BORDER="0" ALT="" ALIGN="right"></A>-->

  </section>
</page>
