<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="default.xsl" ?>
<page title="FAQ">
  
  <section title="It doesn't work, what now?">
    <p>
      The following frequently asked questions along with answers will
      provide you with some solutions to common errors, problems or
      misunderstandings when you try to compile, use or get otherwise
      involved with Pingus.
    </p>
  </section>

  <div id="faqtoc"/>
  <section title="FAQs - Frequently Asked Questions (and Answers)">
    <faq-list>
      <faq date="21. Jul 2003">
        <question>Where can I find more levels?</question>
        <answer>
          <em>Foreword: Every level that isn't reachable via the GUI in
          Pingus is unsupported and might be completly broken, if you
          want to try them you are on your own.</em><br /><br />

          Beside the 22 tested and cleaned up levels of the first
          island that come with Pingus, there are also around 120
          levels that might be playable and another 100 levels that
          are incomplete at the moment. These levels can be found in
          the <tt>data/levels/playable</tt> and
          <tt>data/levels/wip/</tt> (wip = Work in Progress). The
          levels in <tt>playable/</tt> might be playable, but there is
          no guarantee for that, they havn't been tested, might be
          broken due to engine changes, might be far too easy or far
          too hard or simply incomplete. The <tt>wip/</tt> directory
          contains levels that are not playable at all, some of them
          might even lack entrances or exit, so don't even think of
          'playing' them, instead they can be used as framework for
          levels you want to create yourself with the level editor.
          That said, yep, Pingus contains a fully working level
          editor, it might not be 100% bug free, but it was used to
          construct all the levels that you can see in the game. So
          don't hesitate and try it out and build your own levels.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="21. Aug 2003">
        <question>Where can I find the Windows version?</question>

        <answer>
          A official Windows version of 0.6.0 got never created and
          never will be created, but we hope to provide one with
          0.6.1, which will be equal to 0.6.0, but include fixed
          fonts, corrected text and a few minor bugfixes.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="15. Dec 2002">
        <question>How can I get Pingus?</question>
        <answer>
          Pingus is <a
            href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html">Free
            Software</a> under the <a
            href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html">GNU GPL</a>,
          that means everybody can download it, distribute it, modify
          it and even distribute modified works, as long as the source
          code is still provided (checkout the GNU GPL itself for more
          details). That also means that Pingus is available at no
          cost from this webpage and will be available for no cost
          from this website in the future. But it also means that
          Pingus is available from other websites and places, for
          example most GNU/Linux distributions contain a (sometimes
          outdated) version of Pingus, there might be some shareware
          sites which contain a version of Pingus and you can even buy
          game-packs which contain Pingus.<br /> <br />
          
          But the latest version that you can get from this site is
          the only version that is supported, so if you have another
          version and have some problem, the only answer you might get
          is that you should get a new version from this site.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="14. Sep 2003">
        <question>How much does it cost?</question>
        <answer>
          As the question above answers, Pingus is available at no
          costs from this webpage. However you are welcome to make <a
          href="https://www.paypal.com/xclick/business=grumbel%40gmx.de&amp;item_name=Pingus+donation&amp;no_note=1&amp;tax=0&amp;currency_code=EUR">donations
          to Pingus via Paypal</a>. Pingus is after all a voluntary
          project and if you don't have the time to help with
          developing it, you are very welcome to help with a little
          money.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="15. Dec 2002">
        <question>Which Pingus version should I use?</question> 
        <answer>
          As the previous answer told you, Pingus is available from a
          number of places, that also means that not all places will have
          the most current versions, some will probably ship an outdated
          version or an not even working version. So if you want the
          newest version <a href="http://pingus.seul.org">the official
            Pingus webpage</a> will always be the best place to search for a
          new one.<br /><br />

          If you are a gamer it is strongly recommended that you use only
          the version that is marked as playable and stable, all other
          versions, be it the current CVS or a beta-snapshot release, are
          not recommended since they will either spoil the story, new
          levels, gadgets and other things or confuse you with unfinished,
          buggy features. CVS or beta-snapshots might also delete
          your savegames, game statistics or do other thing that ruin your
          fun.<br /><br />

          If you want to test the current development version, want to
          search for bugs and are prepared to find bugs it is of course
          recommended that you stick to a current CVS checkout or the
          beta-snapshots, since testing the stable version will not be
          of much help a few weeks after the release, since most bugs
          might already be fixed by then in the development versions.<br
            /><br />

          If you are a developer and want to look at the code its
          recommended that you stick to current CVS, it might not always be
          100% correct and compile correctly, but it should always be pretty
          close to it. If you encounter problems, just contact one of the
          authors and the problem might be fixed within a few hours.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="15. Dec 2002">
        <question>How to compiling Pingus?</question>
        <answer>
          Under GNU/Linux Pingus should compile like most other
          software, a simple <tt class="command">./configure
          &amp;&amp; make</tt> should do. To install Pingus type <tt
          class="command">make install</tt>, but that is not recommended
          with the development versions, since it might not work or
          worse do ugly things to your file system layout, you can just
          run Pingus directly from the source tree, so there is no
          need to install it.<br /><br />

          But be warned, Pingus need ClanLib and Hermes to be correctly
          installed and to have the right version, so it might
          <em>not</em> be really trivial. Unless you are a developer or
          beta tester it is therefore strongly recommended that you stick
          with the binaries that are provided in the <a
            href="download.html">download section</a> of this site.

          If you want to compile Pingus on Win32, you will need
          Microsoft Visual C++ Version 6 or higher, project files are in
          the Pingus source tree. But again, you need ClanLib and
          Hermes, so it might not be really a trivial task. Pingus will
          currently not compile with Cygwin or Mingw, sorry, porting
          help is of course welcome.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="15. Dec 2002">
        <question>I tried compiling it, but something didn't work</question>
        <answer>
          First of all try to find out at which point it 'didn't work'.
          If it failed at the <tt>./configure</tt> step, you might be
          missing a correctly installed Hermes or ClanLib, the file
          <tt>config.log</tt> might provide you with more information. If it
          fails at <tt>make</tt> time it is most likely a bug in the
          source, such as some C++ construct that requires a g++ larger
          than 3.0, some simple typo, a missing include or other things
          that might not show up on the developers machine, a bug report
          is very welcome in such cases. Make sure that you include the
          exact error message and version of Pingus and ClanLib in your
          bug report.<br /><br />
          
          If Pingus compiled fine, but failed at startup with a message
          like <tt>Couldn't open libsomething.so</tt>, you most likely
          haven't run <tt>ldconfig</tt> after installing ClanLib or
          <tt>/usr/local/lib</tt> is missing from your
          <tt>/etc/ld.so.conf</tt>, in that case <tt>ldconfig</tt> won't
          look at the correct places to find the libraries.
        </answer>
      </faq>
      
      <faq date="22. Dec 2002">
        <question>Why is Pingus still not done? Many years have past and
          it can't be that difficult to write a simple Lemmings clone, can
          it?</question>

        <answer>Well, there are several factors which took Pingus to
          take that long and still cause many delays. First of all Pingus
          was my first larger C++ project, so it was after all a project
          for myself to learn C++, but that also caused a lot of things to
          be done wrong which I needed to rewrite or fix at a later point.
          Pingus also as the problem of being over-engineered at a few
          points, to much abstraction at places way it doesn't make sense
          and only causes problems. So in the end there was lot of cruft
          collected in the first two years which needed to be cleaned up
          in the next years. At this point the code is a lot cleaner than
          back than, but still has some ugly points in it which needs to
          be fixed before the next release.<br />

          Beside the ugly-code issue one also has to see that Pingus is
          a huge game, it isn't a small game like a simple Tetris clone.
          It contains close to 800 unique graphics, 200 levels and 50'000
          lines of code, all these aren't created over night. It might
          have been possible to create this in a year, but motivation
          comes and goes and so there where month were simply nothing
          happens and weeks were large parts of the code got
          restructured or rewritten.<br />
          
          Beside all that its <em>you</em> that could make the
          development go faster by contributing something to the
          project. You don't need coding skills for that, play testing
          the beta versions alone could be a big help if you send in
          helpful comments.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="22. Dec 2002">
        <question>
          Pingus runs to slowly, any way to make it faster?
        </question>

        <answer>
          There are multiple ways to tune Pingus speed. First of if your
          computer is to slow and runs at 24 or 32bit color depth
          switching it down to 16bit might give you a boost of around
          50% percent, depending on your hardware. X11 doesn't allow
          switching color depth at run time, so well this is a bit
          ugly.<br/>

          If you can't switch down the color depth, don't want to or it
          is still to slow you can switch down Pingus to 640x480, that
          can be done by starting it via:<br/>
          
          <tt>pingus -g 640x480</tt><br/>

          If that still doesn't help you can run Pingus in
          <em>fast-mode</em>, it disables all costly particle effects
          and the background, thus Pingus will look more ugly, but will
          probably be a good amount faster. Fast-mode can be turned on with:<br/>

          <tt>pingus --fast-mode</tt><br/>

          You might also play with the <tt>min-frame-skip</tt> and
          <tt>max-frame-skip</tt> options, both should result in a more
          uniform frame-rate, even so it will be a bit more jerky, but
          playability can be increased by that non the less.<br/>

          You can also of course combine all the above and with 'F11'
          you can enable the frame-counter which should help you
          optimising the game. If you have a good configuration for your
          system, please mail it to <a href="mailto:grumbel@gmx.de">Ingo
            Ruhnke</a> along with a description of your system. At a later
          point all this might probably get auto-detected and the
          fast-mode also contains lots of room for optimizations, so if
          it is still not fast enough not all is lost.
        </answer>
      </faq>
    </faq-list>
  </section>
</page>