<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="default.xsl" ?>
<page title="FAQ">
  
  <section title="It doesn't work! What now?">
    <p>
      The following frequently asked questions (along with answers) will
      provide you with solutions some to common errors, problems or
      misunderstandings when you try to compile, use or get otherwise
      involved with Pingus.
    </p>
  </section>

  <div id="faqtoc"/>
  <section title="FAQs - Frequently Asked Questions (and Answers)">
    <faq-list>
	  <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>What is Pingus?</question>
        <answer>
        The <a href="welcome.html">Welcome</a> page answers this question.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>How much does it cost?</question>
        <answer>
        We believe that you should answer this question for yourself.  If you
        think this game is worth some amount of money, you can <a
        href="https://www.paypal.com/xclick/business=grumbel%40gmx.de&amp;item_name=Pingus+donation&amp;no_note=1&amp;tax=0&amp;currency_code=EUR">donate
        to Pingus via Paypal</a>. Otherwise, you can get the game for no
        monetary cost.  Pingus is <a
        href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html">Free Software</a> and
        you are not forced to pay any amount of money for this game.
        </answer>
      </faq>		

      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>Where can I get Pingus?</question>
        <answer>
        You can get Pingus from the <a href="download.html">download</a> section.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>Is there a Windows version?</question>
        <answer>
          An official Windows version of 0.6.0 was never
          created and probably never will be.  However, we hope to
          provide a Windows binary with the 0.6.1 release. It will
          be equal to 0.6.0 plus fixed fonts, corrected text, and a
          few minor bugfixes.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>Where can I find more levels?</question>
        <answer>
          <em>Foreword: Every level that isn't reachable via the GUI in Pingus
          is unsupported and might be completely broken. If you want to try
          them you are on your own.</em> <br /><br />

          Besides the 22 tested and cleaned up levels of the first island that
          come with Pingus. There are also around 120 levels that might be
          playable and another 100 levels that are incomplete at the moment.
          These levels can be found in the <tt>data/levels/playable</tt> and
          <tt>data/levels/wip/</tt> (wip = work in progress). The levels in the
          <tt>playable/</tt> directory might be playable, but there is no
          guarantee for that. They haven't been tested. They might be broken
          due to engine changes.  They might be far too easy or far too hard or
          simply incomplete. The <tt>wip/</tt> directory contains levels that
          are not playable at all. Some of them might even lack entrances
          and/or exits. Don't be surprised that you can't play them. Instead,
          these levels  can be used as framework for levels you want to create
          yourself with the level editor.  Yes, you heard it right, Pingus
          comes with a fully working level editor. It might not be 100% bug
          free, but it was used to construct all the levels that you see in the
          game, so don't hesitate to try it out and build your own levels.
        </answer>
      </faq>


      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>What does it mean for Pingus to be Free Software?</question>
        <answer>
          Pingus is licensed under a <a
          href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html">Free/Libre
          Software</a> license called <a
          href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html">GNU GPL</a>.
          Basically, this means that everybody is free to download,
          distribute, and modify it. Moreover, anyone can distribute
          modified works of Pingus, as long as those works are
          disributed under a <a
          href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/license-list.html#GPLCompatibleLicenses">GPL
          compatible license</a>. In other words, Pingus respects your
          software freedoms.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>How do I compile Pingus?</question>
        <answer>
          Under GNU/Linux run
           <tt class="command">./configure
          &amp;&amp; make</tt> in the source directory.
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
         <question>What are the required built-time libraries?</question>
         <answer>
         Pingus needs specific versions of ClanLib and Hermes. Running the <tt
         class="command">./configure</tt> script will tell you if you whether
         your system has them.
         </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>What do I need for compiling Pingus on a Windows system?</question>
        <answer>
         If you want to compile Pingus on Win32, you will need Microsoft Visual
         C++ Version 6 or higher. Project files are in the Pingus source tree.
         Again, you need ClanLib and Hermes. Pingus will currently not compile
         with Cygwin or Mingw, sorry, porting help is, of course, welcome.
        </answer>
      </faq>
      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>Can I run Pingus from the source directory?</question>
        <answer>
           Yes
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>I tried compiling it, but something didn't work!</question>
        <answer>
          Technically, this isn't a question. You have to be more specific. A
          general suggestion is to search the <a
          href="http://savannah.nongnu.org/bugs/?group=pingus">But Tracker</a>
          for similar problems.
        </answer>
      </faq>
      
      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>
          Why is Pingus still not done after being in development for so many years?
        </question>
        <answer>
          There are several factors that contributed to the long
          development time.  Some of them still cause delays. <br />
          First of all, Pingus was my first large C++ project. After
          all this started as a project for learning C++.  As a
          result, a lot of things have been done wrong, and I needed
          to rewrite or fix them at a later time.<br /><br />

          Pingus also has the problem of being
          over-engineered in a few places. There was too much
          abstraction in places where it doesn't make sense and only
          caused problems. So during the first two years a lot of
          cruft accumulated which needed to be cleaned up in the next
          years. The current code is much cleaner, but it still has
          some ugly points. They are the focus of the next release.
          <br /><br />

          Beside the ugly-code issue one also has to realize
          that Pingus is more complex than it seems. It isn't
          a small game like a Tetris clone would be. It contains close
          to 800 unique graphics, 200 levels and 50'000 lines of code.
          All of that hasn't been created over night. It might have
          been possible to create this in a year, but motivation comes
          and goes. As a result, there were month where simply nothing
          happened and weeks where large parts of the code got
          restructured or rewritten.<br /><br />

          Besides all that, <em>you</em> can make the
          development go faster by contributing something to the
          project.
        </answer>
      </faq>
      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>How can I help the development of Pingus?</question>
        <answer> This project needs help in the following areas:
          <ul>
            <li>Writing documentation</li>
            <li>Writing stories</li>
            <li>Programming
              <ul>
              <li>debugging the editor</li>
              <li>making code 64-bit friendly</li>
              <li>allowing for cygwin/mingw compilation</li>
              <li>porting from Clanlib to SDL</li>
              </ul>
            </li>
            <li>Play testing</li>
          </ul>
        </answer>
      </faq>

      <faq date="14 Jan 2007">
        <question>
          Pingus runs too slow. Is there any way to make it faster?
        </question>

        <answer>
          There are multiple ways to tune the running speed of
          Pingus. <br /> Firstly, reducing the screen colour
          depth (to 16bit, for example) on a slower computer might
          give you a boost of around 50% percent, depending on your
          hardware. X11 doesn't allow switching color depth at run
          time, and the exact instructions for doing this are outside
          of the scope of this FAQ. Consult your distribution
          documentation for more information.<br /><br />

          Secondly, a gain in speed can be achieved by
          reducing the display resolution of Pingus. For example, if
          you want to run Pingus at 640x480 you can do this with the
          following command:<br />

          <tt>pingus -g 640x480</tt><br/><br />

          Thirdly, you can run Pingus in a <em>fast-mode</em>.
          This mode disables all costly particle effects and the
          background.  Thus, Pingus will look more ugly, but will
          probably be a good amount faster. Fast-mode can be turned on
          with:<br />

          <tt>pingus --fast-mode</tt><br/> Remember, the
          <em>fast-mode</em> has lots of room for improvement. If it
          doesn't help you make Pingus run fast enough, not all is
          lost. <br /><br />

          If that is not enough, you might also want to play
          with the <tt>min-frame-skip</tt> and <tt>max-frame-skip</tt>
          options.  Both should result in a more uniform frame-rate.
          This can make the game jerky, but playability can be
          improved nonetheless.<br /><br />

          Finally, the 'F11' key can help you a great deal in
          your optimisation process by showing the frame-rate counter.
          <br /><br />

          If you have a good configuration for your system,
          please mail it to <a href="mailto:grumbel@gmx.de">Ingo
          Ruhnke</a> along with a description of your system. At a
          later point all this info could be used to write an
          auto-detection algorithm for optimizing Pingus.
        </answer>
      </faq>
    </faq-list>
  </section>
</page>
